We sigh whenever we're about to come to a standstill
Owarinaki tabi no tochuu tachidomarisouna toki
While moving on this endless journey.
Fukai tameiki kobosu bokura wa
Everytime we lunge for it, it escapes and flies off.
Tsukamikaketewa mata hanareteitta
But now, there's nothing to be afraid of
Demo ima wa mou nanimo osoreru koto wa nai
The powerful ties that bind our hearts
Kokoro wo tsunagu tsuyoi kizuna wa
Will never come loose.
Keshite hodoke wa shinai sa
After a lifetime of searching, we finally arrived
Sagashitsuzukete tadoritsuita
Here, where the period lies.
Kono basho de piriodo ni
Let's change all our sorrow and rage to power.
Kanashimi ikari chikara ni kaete
Destiny is right within our reach.
Unmei wa sugu soba ni
So you're suggesting Major General Armstrong had a hand in Lieutenant General Raven's disappearance?
Most likely.
But I'm sure she left no evidence.
You're right.
Ah, well. Our job is to take over this fort...
...while that fox is being investigated in Central by a herd of tigers.
Oh, if it isn't the Major General.
I still can't believe you were transferred to Central.
What connections did you use?
I believe it's simply an honest display of my capabilities.
Says the fresh meat.
What brings you here today?
I've been summoned by the Führer President.
I may not be able to return to Briggs for a while.
"For a while"?
Then I'm going to have to take you to dinner at least once.
Is it your treat?
If you'll let me eat until you go bankrupt, I don't mind going for dinner.
I guess I'll give up on the meal, then...
Both your wallet and your balls are pea-sized, I see.
How about some flowers instead?
There are many great florists in Central, after all.
I see.
You may enter.
Yes, sir.
Now, Major General Armstrong...
...let me hear more about
Lieutenant General Raven's disappearance.
What did you do?
I won't be able to hide this.
Why would a man as great as you choose to place a fool like Raven by his side?
So you got rid of him?
You don't need him.
Having a subordinate with such a loose tongue would do you no good.
What did Lieutenant General Raven tell you?
Something about an immortal army...
...the history of this country, and your real identity.
He told me many things I didn't even ask for.
So you still chose to respond to
my summons after hearing all that?
Yes, to request the seat the idiot had been placing his ass on.
Interesting, as expected of you.
Very well. You may have the position.
In exchange, I'll have one of my men govern over Briggs. Are you fine with this?
As you wish, sir.
They are powerful soldiers I trained with great care.
I'm sure you'll like them.
Interesting. Do your best, human.
"Nothing ventured, nothing gained."
So the Major General ventured into the enemy's lair by her own will.
Yeah. This place also belongs to them now.
But they're unaware...
...Briggs is a giant monolith that can act with a united will, even if its master happens to be away.
From here on, it's a war between bears and tigers.
Homunculus
(The Dwarf in the Flask)
Is that seat free?
Yes.
How's your work progressing?
As you can see,
I can't finish everything unless I multitask during my meals, as well.
And you?
There's so much to memorize; I'm fairly busy.
But the Führer President does his job very quickly, so I do not have to worry about that.
He doesn't loaf either, unlike a certain someone.
I have a feeling this topic is heading in a direction I don't like.
That reminds me...
Scar is apparently up north.
So are the Elric brothers.
I see.
My old classmates, Lucy and Ian, are also up north.
They tell me many things.
If I recall, the north and the east will be holding joint exercises in the spring.
Yes, we've been defeated countless times by Major Miles and Captain Buccaneer.
Miles... Buccaneer...
York, Ida, and Sugar, too.
Havoc, Oscar, Mike, Uni, Nora, Charley...
Uni again, then Lucy...
Uni comes again, then next... is Sterling!
"Selim Bradley is Homunculus".
I guess there's no way that can't  be true.
Just what is about to happen here in Central?
Boy.
Hey, you over there.
Oh, crap!
Don't worry.
Over here.
What the hell?
Come on.
Aren't you at least a little surprised?
If I do get surprised, will you give me something?
I guess you're always at ease. I like you.
What's your name?
Slave Number 23.
I didn't ask for a number. I want your real name.
I don't have a name. I'm a slave.
Slave?
People who are stripped of their rights and freedom, and are exchanged as possessions in conveyance?
Conveyance?
To transfer property and rights and such.
You're not very bright, are you?
Shut up!
I don't understand how I was born from someone like you.
You're the one who gave me blood, aren't you?
They did take a lot of blood from me to use for experiments...
I was born because you gave me blood.
Thank you. Umm...
"Slave Number 23" just sounds too cold.
I'll give you a name, then.
Who the hell do you think you are?
Don't you want a cool name? Let's see...
Teo... Teofrastus Bombastus.
Too long.
Ah, it can't be too long; else you won't be able to memorize it. You're dumb, after all.
Quit saying that!
Then how about Van?
Van Hohenheim.
Van Hohen, eh?
I should be able to remember that.
You spell it like...
Wait, do you know how to read and write?
I don't need to know to work.
The work of a slave, right?
Don't you want freedom and rights?
Do you plan on ending your life as a slave without gaining basic human rights?
That's the same as being in this stuffy flask.
I'm going to share my knowledge with you, Van Hohenheim.
Hey... What are  you?
What should I call you?
The Little One Inside the Flask. So... call me "Homunculus".
All was created from one, and it eventually returns to one.
In other words, one is all.
All exists due to one...
...and all exists within one.
If one does not contain all, then there exists nothing.
You pass.
You're now a fine alchemist, Hohenheim.
I'm still not good enough to be on my own.
My abilities are far beneath yours, Master.
You know, I'm really thankful.
For what?
Because you gave me knowledge,
I'm able to live a good life like this.
I'm also happy to be in Master's favor.
It may be possible that I can marry someone in the future and start my own family.
A family, eh?
Humans are inconvenient creatures, aren't they?
The species can't live on unless they all create a community and expand.
Don't talk like that.
It may be stupid in your eyes,
but having friends and family...
...may bring one happiness.
For us humans, that is.
Really?
Then what do you consider happiness?
Let's see...
I don't want to be too greedy, but I guess being able to leave this flask would make me happy.
Immortality...
I wonder why fools who gained ultimate authority and prosperity begin to wish for that.
Mind your tongue!
You're talking to the King!
If you continue to be disrespectful, I'll break the flask!
You're going to destroy the source of the knowledge you don't know about?
Cease your prattling.
Can you make me immortal or not?
Growing impatient as you age, huh?
How sad, King of Xerxes.
Fine, I'll tell you how to achieve immortality.
What's with the construction?
We're making a waterway for irrigation.
The King ordered a waterway to extend around the entire country.
Nothing less to be expected from the King of Xerxes.
He even thinks about commoners like us.
That's right.
Kill them all. Understood?
Yes, sir!
Hurry! Waste no time!
Hurry and carve a bloody crest into the land!
The village to the north was raided?
I heard everyone there was killed.
And the same thing happened in the village to the west last time.
I wonder who's behind it...
How terrible.
Yeah, how awful.
Your Majesty, the transmutation circle is finally complete.
Truly, it has been a long time.
This is all we need to do, right?
Yeah, you'll be able to become immortal.
That's amazing.
The King is going to become immortal.
I guess it's what they call the turning point of the century.
So this is immortality...
What's this?!
You said that since we're in the center of it, we wouldn't be harmed!
What?
What's happening?!
Hey! Homunculus!
The true center of the transmutation circle is where you're standing right now.
What?!
I opened the gate using your blood inside of me.
You're a relative that shares my blood, Hohenheim!
Right now, you and I are at the center of the world!
Your Majesty!
Master!
He's dead.
Is anyone here?!
Willard!
Mechthild!
Linemile!
Tony!
Meiyou!
Please... Someone, say something.
It's no use. Everyone has had their souls taken from them.
Your Majesty!
You were all right...
So...
...How do you like your new body?
It's... me...
I created a body for myself using
the information stored in your blood.
Finally, I can walk with my own two feet.
You're... Homunculus?
What is this?! What did you do?!
In return for you giving me blood, I gave you a name and shared my knowledge with you.
I also gave you an eternal body.
Eternal?
Try focusing all of your consciousness into yourself.
Can't you hear the voices?
The voices of all the people, who lived in this country, sacrificed for your immortal body.
Well, half of them went to me.
Thanks for your help, Hohenheim.
Mr. Hohenheim?
It really is  you!
Wow, I didn't know you were Ed and Al's father.
I didn't expect you to be the master of my sons, either...
I hear you did a lot for them.
No, not at all.
Miss Izumi?
Are you all right, Izumi?!
I'll get your medicine...
Let me take a look at her.
I know a thing or two about medicine.
Don't worry, this isn't anything new.
This is certainly something to worry about.
Mr. Sig, please get a cab.
Hurry!
R-Right!
Miss Izumi...
You saw the truth, didn't you?
What did you sacrifice?
Please don't try to hide it.
They took a few of my organs.
I tried to revive my dead baby.
I see.
I see...
If you'll excuse me.
Izumi! Hang in there!
Izumi!
Calm down, Dear. I'm fine.
You were stabbed in the stomach!
But I can breathe more easily now.
Show me your wound.
There's no wound.
That can't be!
The organs that were taken are the proof of your sins, so I can't bring them back.
But I rearranged your insides a bit to ease the flow of blood.
Miss Izumi, you can't die just yet.
Hohenheim...
Just... what exactly are  you?
I'm a human by the name of Van Hohenheim...
A philosopher's stone in human form.
The promise we never made
Kawashita hazu no nai yakasoku ga
yet again
Kyou mo
tries to snatch our future away from us.
Bokura no mirai wo ubaou to suru
Why is it that we can't rejoice
Hoshigatteita mono wo te ni shitemo
straight from the heart
Sunao ni
when we obtain something we've always been after?
Umaku waraenai nowa nazedarou
The overflowing tears aren't from feebleness or remorse.
Afureru namida wo yowasa ya koukai ja nai
They're fragments born from agony.
Itami ga unda kakera de
Of all the moments and destinies,
Donna shunkan datte unmei datte
I realized there's one absolute certainty.
Hitotsu dake tashika na mono ga aru to shitta
Even if things get tough and I'm at my limit
Genkai datte konnan datte
I refuse to give up.
Akirametakunaiyo
Please, don't let go.
Konomama hanasanaide
I can feel the warmth of your right hand
Kataku nigirishimeta kimi no migite no nukumori
where it's tightly joined with my left.
Koko ni arukara
The Philosopher's Stone,
the Heavenly Stone, the Great Elixir.
Just like how the philosopher's stone has many names,
its form isn't always that of a stone.
The one Doctor Marcoh had was almost like a gel.
Kimblee's looked like a crystal, and it was about this big.
Since it possesses so much energy, I pictured something far larger...
I've never seen one bigger than a pebble.
If it's something even larger, that would mean an enormous number of humans was used to create it.
I'd rather not see one.
If one wishes to gain something,
one must present something of equal value.
That is the principle behind alchemy.
It is also the principle behind everything else.
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
The Abyss
Episode 41, The Abyss.
His softness seeks pain from the boy as an equal exchange.